Elizabeth Ahn Toupin Papers MS064
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Elizabeth Ahn Toupin Papers
1935 -- 2013
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Toupin, Elizabeth Ahn
MS064
6 Linear Feet 5 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Tufts Subject Files; Chinese Artists at Tufts; Professional Activities; Publications and Presentations; and Personal and Family.
Custodial History
Toupin put sticky notes with numbers in certain folders that correspond to an inventory list. The sticky notes were kept in the folders, though the inventory list has not been found. It may be in the collection. In 2010, Toupin also weeded and rearranged her own materials, and added comments to some folders providing context as to what is included, and these annotations have been kept.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Elizabeth Ahn Toupin, former Jackson College Director of Student Affairs and Assistant Dean and Tufts Associate Dean of Undergraduate Education. It contains biographical information, material related to Toupin's professional activities, correspondence, photographs, cookbooks and other publications, speeches, an oral history, and unpublished manuscripts, including the incomplete memoirs of her years at Tufts. It also contains information about the Asian artists that Toupin helped bring to Tufts. The bulk of this collection dates from the late 1960s through the late 1990s and relates to her professional roles.
Related Materials
Papers of Elizabeth Ahn Toupin, 1962-2010, Schlesinger Library.
Drucker Archives, Claremont Colleges.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Ahn Toupin (1925-) served as Director of Student Affairs and Assistant Dean of Jackson College, and Associate Dean of Undergraduate Education at Tufts University.
Toupin was born and raised in Honolulu, Hawaii to South Korean immigrants Won Kiu and Chung Song Ahn, supporters of the Korean independence movement. As a child she was trained in Hawaiian and Korean dance, and her sister Florence became a renowned classical singer. Toupin graduated from Bennington College-- where she was a student of Peter Drucker-- with a bachelor's degree in economics in 1948. She later received a master's degree in industrial relations from the University of Hawaii and Cornell University in 1950. After graduation, Toupin worked as a media consultant for Senator Daniel Inouye (Hawaii), and authored numerous cookbooks. In 1950, she married Richard Toupin, a physics instructor she met at the University of Hawaii. They had three children, and divorced in 1967.
Toupin came to work at Tufts University in May of 1968 as Director of Student Affairs at Jackson College, and in 1969, became Assistant Dean of Jackson under Antonia Chayes, then Dean of Jackson College. During her tenure she oversaw drastic changes in the policies regarding privacy and parietals in the dorms at Jackson, which led to one of the first co-ed dorms in the United States (the Tufts Divinity School maintained a co-ed house in the 1890's). As part of her responsibilities, she was engaged in providing safe ways for students to demonstrate and express their opinions about political and social conflicts of the day, including the Vietnam War, ROTC, and racial issues. In particular, this included the "construction crisis" of 1969, when students protested the lack of Black and other minority workers involved in new construction projects on campus.
In 1979, Toupin was appointed Associate Dean of Undergraduate Education. Her new responsibilities included initiating and overseeing informal learning situations and extracurricular programs at Tufts. This included the SPIRIT program (Society for the Propagation of Internal Rejoicing at Tufts), the internship program, the "All That Jazz" series (which brought jazz greats to campus including, among others, BB King), the Re-Entry Committee (a group concerned with students returning after a leave for mental health reasons), and the Artist in Residence program (which brought Irene Worth, Yo-Yo Ma, and numerous Asian artists to campus). The Artist in Residence program was partially funded by the Toupin-Bolwell Fund for the Arts, established in 1986 to honor Suzanne Bolwell and Dean Toupin for their support of the arts. The fund still exists in 2014.
Throughout her career Toupin worked for the integration and equality of women and minorities at Tufts, and was an essential advocate for the Asian American and African American communities on campus. She taught courses and held conferences at Tufts relating to Asian American issues, and helped to bring Asian artists such as Yuan Yunsheng, Qui Deshu, and Wang Keping to campus.
Toupin also led an extensive professional life outside of Tufts. She lectured at other local colleges and universities including Brandeis, Harvard, Simmons, and Wellesley, especially surrounding issues relating to women, mental health, and the performing arts. She also consulted for various organizations, including the United States Department of Defense as part of the Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services (DACOWITS). Toupin was also active on various committees and boards including the Baybanks Middlesex Regional Board, the Museum of Science Overseers, Oxfam, the Asian American Policy Review board, and the board of the Cambridge Adult Education Center. She published numerous articles, including the controversial study "Preliminary findings on Asian-Americans: 'The model minority' in a small private east coast college," which challenged the stereotype of Asian Americans as a model minority. Toupin also worked on a memoir (incomplete as of 2014) that largely presents a critical detailed history of Tufts during the late 1960's and early 1970's.
Toupin was much renowned for her work, and received awards including the Zonta Club of Medford's Woman of Achievement award in 1987. She retired from Tufts in 1991, and was appointed Acting Director of American Studies from 1992-1993. She received an emerita degree from Tufts in 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Faculty papers; University history; Greater Boston arts; Toupin, Elizabeth Ahn
- Tufts Subject Files, 1961 -- 2012; MS064.001; 2.4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence, clippings, programs, posters, course material, conference materials, letters of recommendation for students and colleagues, and other material relating to Toupin's professional activities at Tufts.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - Afro Construction Crisis, 1969; MS064.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Afro Society, 1969; MS064.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz Billy Taylor, 1980; MS064.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz B. B. King, 1982 -- 1987; MS064.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz Women & All That Jazz, 1985; MS064.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz (7th) George Russell, 1987; MS064.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz, 1985 -- 1989; MS064.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz, 1989 -- 1990; MS064.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz Dizzy Gillespie, 1977; MS064.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - All That Jazz - Jazz Week, 1982 -- 1990; MS064.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - The Last "All That Jazz" Poster - Concert "snowed out", 1989; MS064.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Studio Red Top, 1986; MS064.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - WGBH - American Mosaic Advisory Board, 1986 -- 1987; MS064.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - American Studies, 1982 -- 1993; MS064.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Ammons, Elizabeth, 1989 -- 1996; MS064.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, T. J., 1989 -- 2006; MS064.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Conference, 1983; MS064.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Asian Americans - Cornell Conference, 1986; MS064.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Asian-American Course A. S., 1981 -- 1986; MS064.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Course AS 180 Asian Am in 20th Cent. American Studies, 1980 -- 1986; MS064.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Tufts Asian-American Roots Literature, 1976 -- 1986; MS064.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Data, 1987; MS064.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Fund, 1994; MS064.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Short Stories & other, 1988; MS064.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Asian Americans Tufts Students Essays, 1983 -- 1986; MS064.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - Asian American Alliance, 1986 -- 1988; MS064.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Studies & Conference Asian American Writers Letters, 1990; MS064.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Asian Women's Conference, 1990; MS064.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Janice Mirikitani, 1984 -- 2008; MS064.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Maxine Hong Kingston, 1981 -- 1991; MS064.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Studies Incoming, 1981 -- 1990; MS064.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Study - Final, 1985 -- 2005; MS064.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Asian Student Incident, 1982 -- 2007; MS064.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Asian Students - Zeta Psi, 1982 -- 2007; MS064.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Women Writers Conference 1990 [1 of 3], 1990 -- 1991; MS064.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Women Writers Conference 1990 [2 of 3], 1989 -- 1990; MS064.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Women Writers Conference 1990 [3 of 3], MS064.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Asian American Women Writers Bio's - Correspondence, 1990; MS064.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Bio & Personnel Notes, 1968 -- 1992; MS064.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Black Students [1 of 2], 1969 -- 2007; MS064.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Black Students [2 of 2], 1971 -- 1974; MS064.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Black Writers Conference, 1981; MS064.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Bolwell Fund, 1985 -- 2010; MS064.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Art at Tufts, 1991 -- 2007; MS064.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Arts Article, 1985 -- 1992; MS064.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Fund for the Arts Yo Yo Ma, 1984 -- 1992; MS064.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Campus Issue for the New Minority Asian American Students, 1984; MS064.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Chayes, Toni [1 of 2], 1968 -- 1970; MS064.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Chayes, Toni [2 of 2], 1969 -- 1970; MS064.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Chayes, Toni and Tufts History, 1968 -- 1969; MS064.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988; MS064.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Data - Minority Students, 1978 -- 1984; MS064.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Former Staff Correspondence, 1981 -- 1991; MS064.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Freshman, 1982 -- 1989; MS064.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Arlo Guthrie, 1987 -- 1988; MS064.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Israel Horovitz, 1984 -- 1987; MS064.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - 68-70 Housing Report Jackson, 1968 -- 1969; MS064.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Housing Report, 1971, 1970 -- 1974; MS064.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - Latin American Teaching Fellowships, 1972 -- 2012; MS064.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - Letters of Reccommendation (Colleagues), 1981 -- 1992; MS064.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Letters of Reccommendation (Students), 1986 -- 1991; MS064.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - Liz Papers, 1961 -- 1993; MS064.001.002.00001 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Lurias, 1973 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00002 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
    correspondence with Zella and Salvadore Luria
  - Minority Administrators, 1974 -- 1990; MS064.001.002.00003 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Notes, 1969; MS064.001.002.00004 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Parent Correspondence, 1986 -- 1987; MS064.001.002.00005 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Personnel Issues, 1977 -- 1990; MS064.001.002.00006 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Chet Pierce [1 of 3], 1975 -- 1993; MS064.001.002.00007 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Chet Pierce [2 of 3], 1975 -- 1993; MS064.001.002.00008 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Chet Pierce [3 of 3], 1975 -- 1993; MS064.001.002.00009 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Retirement, 1989 -- 1997; MS064.001.002.00010 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Secretary Cuts, 1982 -- 1990; MS064.001.002.00011 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Spirit, 1988 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00012 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Spirit 1970's Martin Kaplan, 1977 -- 1988; MS064.001.002.00013 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Spirit, 1980 -- 1987; MS064.001.002.00014 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Statistical Data, 1984; MS064.001.002.00015 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Student Correspondence [1 of 5], 1977 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00016 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Student Correspondence [2 of 5], 1977 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00017 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Student Correspondence [3 of 5], 1977 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00018 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Student Correspondence [4 of 5], 1977 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00019 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Student Correspondence [5 of 5], 1977 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00020 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Student Protest and Action, 1969 -- 1970; MS064.001.002.00021 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
    includes ROTC file
  - Student Writings, 1966 -- 1986; MS064.001.002.00022 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Studies:A.Am. And Math, 1980 -- 1988; MS064.001.002.00023 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted, 1980 -- 1994; MS064.001.002.00024 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted: Faculty Correspondence, 1982 -- 2007; MS064.001.002.00025 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted:Non-Faculty Correspondence, 1970 -- 2007; MS064.001.002.00026 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted: Other Universities' Correspondence, 1987 -- 2001; MS064.001.002.00027 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted: Proposals, 1985 -- 1988; MS064.001.002.00028 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted: TU Student Writings (Fiction), MS064.001.002.00029 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Assorted: Studies at Tufts, 1976 -- 1987; MS064.001.002.00030 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Business, 1969 -- 1991; MS064.001.002.00031 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Voices, 1992; MS064.001.002.00032 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Irene Worth [1 of 2], 1980 -- 1998; MS064.001.002.00033 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Irene Worth [2 of 2], 1980 -- 1998; MS064.001.002.00034 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Joe Yamamoto, 1981 -- 1982; MS064.001.002.00035 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Tim Yee, 1990 -- 1995; MS064.001.002.00036 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
- Chinese Artists at Tufts, 1980 -- 2013; MS064.002; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series contains biographical information, correspondence, exhibition programs and text, and publicity material relating to Chinese artists Toupin helped bring to Tufts. This series may also contain informal art by the various artists.
  - Chen, Yifei--Chin. Artist, 1980 -- 1988; MS064.002.002.00037 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Cohen, Joan [1 of 2], 1980 -- 1992; MS064.002.002.00038 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Cohen, Joan (Lebold) [2 of 2], 1982 -- 1998; MS064.002.002.00039 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Deshu, Qiu, 1985 -- 1988; MS064.002.002.00040 (Box MS064 Shared 1)
  - Wang, Keping [1 of 3], 1993 -- 2010; MS064.002.003.00001 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Wang, Keping [2 of 3], 1993 -- 1999; MS064.002.003.00002 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Wang, Keping [3 of 3], 1993 -- 2010; MS064.002.003.00003 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan Yunsheng [1 of 2], 1982 -- 2013; MS064.002.003.00004 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan Yunsheng [2 of 2], 1983 -- 2001; MS064.002.003.00005 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Administrative Details Yungsheng, 1983 -- 1996; MS064.002.003.00006 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan, Yunsheng - Background, 1983 -- 2010; MS064.002.003.00007 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yunsheng - Fund Raising Efforts, 1982 -- 1983; MS064.002.003.00008 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan Yungshen General Corespondence, Expenses, Operation (nose), 1982 -- 2007; MS064.002.003.00009 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan Yunshen at Harvard, 1992 -- 2007; MS064.002.003.00010 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yunsheng - Publicity, MS064.002.003.00011 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yunsheng Reviews, 1983 -- 1996; MS064.002.003.00012 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan Yunsheng - Shows, 1983; MS064.002.003.00013 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yungsheng-Toupin Correspondence, 1983 -- 2010; MS064.002.003.00014 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Yuan, Zuo, 1990 -- 1994; MS064.002.003.00015 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
- Professional Activities, 1961 -- 2008; MS064.003; 2.4 Linear Feet
  This series contains correspondence, scripts, notes, speeches, reviews, clippings, resumes, conference materials, committee reports, and other material relating to Toupin's professional activities outside of Tufts.
  - Air Force Studies, 1977 -- 1981; MS064.003.003.00016 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Alfaro Scripts, 2001; MS064.003.003.00017 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Asian American Drama Conference - Harvard Stud. 1996 Cancelled, 1994 -- 1996; MS064.003.003.00018 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Asian American Institute Foundation, 1987 -- 1995; MS064.003.003.00019 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Asian American Psychiatry, 1982 -- 1984; MS064.003.003.00020 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Asian American Resumes & Bios, 1984 -- 1992; MS064.003.003.00021 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Asian American Stuff - Reviews, Studies, 1984 -- 1989; MS064.003.003.00022 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Asian American Theater, 1994 -- 1996; MS064.003.003.00023 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Awards, 1975 -- 1987; MS064.003.003.00024 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Bennington [1 of 3], 1973 -- 2002; MS064.003.003.00025 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Bennington [2 of 3], 1995 -- 2000; MS064.003.003.00026 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Bennington [3 of 3], 1998 -- 1999; MS064.003.003.00027 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Bennington 50th Reunio, 1972 -- 2002; MS064.003.003.00028 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Board Appointments - Not-Tufts, 1987 -- 2003; MS064.003.003.00029 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Boston Public Schools, 1990 -- 1994; MS064.003.003.00030 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - CAEC - Theater Board, 1994 -- 1996; MS064.003.003.00031 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Kathleen Chang, 1996; MS064.003.003.00032 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Commission on Civil Rights, 1974; MS064.003.003.00033 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Conferences (papers) - 70-80, 1974 -- 1985; MS064.003.003.00034 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Conference (Papers) - 70-80 [participant 1 of 2], 1973 -- 1992; MS064.003.003.00035 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Conference (Papers) - 70-80 [participant 2 of 2], 1984 -- 1987; MS064.003.003.00036 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Consulting, 1990 -- 1993; MS064.003.003.00037 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Correspondence [1 of 2], 1984 -- 1988; MS064.003.003.00038 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Correspondence [2 of 2], 1969 -- 2003; MS064.003.003.00039 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - DACOWITS: Defense Advisory Committee on Women in the Services, 1977 -- 1982; MS064.003.003.00040 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - ECASU, 1992; MS064.003.003.00041 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Ewah College, 1976; MS064.003.003.00042 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Fundraising, 1982 -- 1993; MS064.003.003.00043 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Inouye, D. K. Letters, Speeches, News, 1961 -- 1989; MS064.003.003.00044 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Inouye, D. K. Senator's Letters, 1961 -- 2008; MS064.003.003.00045 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Internment Forum, 1981, 1980 -- 1982; MS064.003.003.00046 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Kim Daejung, 1998; MS064.003.003.00047 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Korean-American Students' Conference [1 of 2], 1987; MS064.003.003.00048 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Korean-American Students' Conference [2 of 2], 1986 -- 1991; MS064.003.003.00049 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Korean Consul, 1989 -- 1992; MS064.003.003.00050 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Letters to Newspapers, 1975 -- 2000; MS064.003.003.00051 (Box MS064 Shared 2)
  - Mental Health Issues for East Coast Asian Students, 1983 -- 1984; MS064.003.004.00001 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Asian-American Conf., 1984; MS064.003.004.00002 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Mental Health of Asian Americans: East Coast Committee Correspondence, 1983 -- 1984; MS064.003.004.00003 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Museum of Science, 1992 -- 2004; MS064.003.004.00004 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - NEMWA, 1974 -- 1984; MS064.003.004.00005 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Other Mental Health Work, 1975 -- 1984; MS064.003.004.00006 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Psychiatric Meetings, 1992; MS064.003.004.00007 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Rue, David, 1991 -- 1992; MS064.003.004.00008 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Summer 1981 UCLA, MS064.003.004.00009 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - USC Korean Lib./Korean Museum, 1999; MS064.003.004.00010 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Women's Cong. Wellesley, Am. Council of Ed., 1974; MS064.003.004.00011 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Workshops (ED), 1987; MS064.003.004.00012 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
- Publications and Presentations, 1959 -- 2009; MS064.004.000001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains cookbooks, published articles, speeches and lectures, an oral history on a cassette tape, and notes for publications or presentations by Toupin. This series also contains the incomplete manuscript of Toupin's memoirs, "Dean's Diary," which contains a critical detailed history of Tufts during the late 1960's and early 1970's.
  - American Journal of Orthopschiatry Vol. 50, No.1, 1980; MS064.004.004.00013 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
    Title: Counseling Asians: Psychotherapy in the Context of Racism and Asian-American History; Publisher: American Orthopsychiatric Association
  - Asian American Policy Review Spring 1990, Vol. 1, MS064.004.004.00014 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
    Title: Public Policy, Higher Education, and the Model Minority; Publisher: Asian American Policy Review, Harvard University and Uiversity of California Berkeley
  - Confrontation Cookbook Manuscript, MS064.004.004.00015 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Dean's Diary Manuscript, MS064.004.004.00016 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - The Entertaining Wife, 1959; MS064.004.004.00017 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
    Title: The Entertaining Wife or the Lady Who Came to Dinner; Publisher: Cornerstone Library
  - Hawaii Cookbook and Backyard Luau, 1967; MS064.004.004.00018 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
    Silvermine Publishers
  - Human Services for Cultural Minorities, 1981; MS064.004.004.00019 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
    Title: Counciling Asians: Psychotherapy in the Context of Racism and Asian-American History; Publisher: University Park Press Baltimore
  - Journal of Cross Cultural Psychology: Asian Americans as the Model Minority, MS064.004.004.00020 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
    Title: Preliminary Findings on Asian Americans: 'The Mdoel Minority' in a Small Private East Coast College; Publisher: Sage Publications
  - Lectures, 1980 -- 1987; MS064.004.004.00021 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Notes re: "Dean's Diary" Memoir, 1969 -- 1970; MS064.004.004.00022 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Notes for Speeches, 1981 -- 1984; MS064.004.004.00023 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Oral History, 2009; MS064.004.004.00024 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Published Works, 1984 -- 1993; MS064.004.004.00025 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Requests for Article, 1979 -- 1984; MS064.004.004.00026 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Research Articles, 1974 -- 1992; MS064.004.004.00027 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Restaurant of the 5 Volcanos Cookbook, 1964; MS064.004.004.00028 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Some Cultural Differences in Response to Coed Housing: A Case Report, 1974; MS064.004.004.00029 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Speeches [1 of 3], 1970 -- 1992; MS064.004.004.00030 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Speeches [2 of 3], 1988 -- 1992; MS064.004.004.00031 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Speeches [3 of 3], 1971 -- 1992; MS064.004.004.00032 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Speeches and Panels Outside of Tufts [1 of 2], 1975 -- 1991; MS064.004.004.00033 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Speeches and Panels Outside of Tufts [2 of 2], 1974 -- 1991; MS064.004.004.00034 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - SW 543: Psychosocial Aspects of Ethnicity, 1988 -- 1989; MS064.004.004.00035 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Ahn Family Correspondence, 2000 -- 2009; MS064.005.004.00036 (Box MS064 Shared 3)
  - Alfaro, Rosanna, 2006 -- 2007; MS064.005.004.00037 (Box MS064 Shared 3)